Guide to the Arboretum at Connecticut College Records, 1890-2016 (inclusive), 1930-1990 (bulk) RG51
Linda Lear Center for Special Collections and Archives
The Arboretum at Connecticut College records
1890-2016 (Inclusive)
1930-1990 (Bulk)
Linda Lear Center for Special Collections and Archives
Avery, George S. (George Sherman), 1903-
Dreyer, Glenn D.
Niering, William A.
Blunt, Katharine, 1876-1954
Black, Caroline A.
Goodwin, Richard H. (Richard Hale), 1910-2007
Branch, Anna Hempstead, 1875-1937
Connecticut College. Arboretum
Connecticut College
RG51
10.06 Linear Feet 23 boxes, 3 oversize folders
2 Gigabytes analog media in folder, digitized audio files
Administrative records, correspondence, and land records documenting the Arboretum at Connecticut College's founding and operations, including extensive information on Arboretum's growth, environmental goals, and operational difficulties from 1930 to 2000s.
Administrative History
The Connecticut College Arboretum (originally the Connecticut Arboretum) was established in 1931 on a 64-acre parcel of land on Williams Street, just to the west of the campus. Seeking a new head of the College's Botany department, President Katharine Blunt believed an arboretum would be an attractive incentive, both as a research facility for the College and as a community resource for the residents of New London.
"Fertile in soil and charming in outlook," this tract of "rolling hills and little valleys," with its craggy granite ledges, bogs, red maple swamp, pine plantations, and hemlock groves, quickly became a favored natural escape for picnickers, hikers, and nature lovers from the College and town alike. In April 1931, Blunt hired New York landscape architect A.F. Brinckerhoff to design a preliminary plan for an arboretum, and appointed newly-hired botany professor George Avery as the Arboretum's first director.
Tasked with the early development and growth of the Arboretum, Avery focused his efforts on establishing a Native Plant Collection, building greenhouses for research, and developing educational efforts and a membership base to help offset operating costs. When Avery left in 1944 for the Brooklyn Botanic Garden, the University of Rochester's Dr. Richard Goodwin was hired to head both the Arboretum and the Botany department. Goodwin oversaw the growth of the Arboretum from 90 acres to more than 450 acres to the west, north, and northeast of campus. Educational and research programs expanded under Goodwin's tenure, as well. In 1952, the Bolleswood tract was established as a site for long-term ecological studies, and a year later, plant ecologist Dr. William Niering was hired to supervise the ecological research program. Over the course of the next two decades, Goodwin and Niering championed land conservation efforts, working with local industrial manufacturers, utilities companies, and the general public to preserve natural areas and protect the region's tidal and freshwater wetlands. They also worked to establish environmental studies (originally human ecology) as a fully-fledged major program within the botany department in 1969. Dr. Niering became director of the Arboretum in 1965, a position he held until 1988, when Glenn Dreyer was hired as the first full-time administrative director and Niering began coordinating research activities. Dreyer changed the name, from the Connecticut Arboretum to the Connecticut College Arboretum, developed an institutional mission, and in 1996, helped develop a campus planning effort that incorporated all Connecticut College land and property – including the main campus – as part of the Arboretum.
References Arboretum Bulletin No. 28 - The Connecticut Arboretum: Its First Fifty Years 1931-1981. New London: Connecticut College, 1981. Arboretum Bulletin No. 32 - The Connecticut College Arboretum: Its Sixth Decade and a Detailed History of the Land. New London: Connecticut College, 1991. Dreyer, Glenn. "History of the Arboretum." Connecticut College, n.d. Web.
Content Description
The collection documents the management and operation of the Arboretum at Connecticut College, including committee and financial reports; correspondence; student research; land acquisition records; maps; deeds; photographs; and publications (Arboretum newsletter, the Bulletin, educational brochures, and lists of flora and fauna on the Connecticut College campus). The Arboretum Advisory Committee Reports contain extensive information concerning the growth, environmental goals, and operational difficulties of the Arboretum from 1930 to 2000s. These records have been divided into eight series: Administrative records, Land records, Programs and events, Arboretum Press and Publicity, Undergraduate Natural Science Studies, Audio and Visual material, and Richard Goodwin's historical research. Series are arranged alphabetically then by date unless otherwise noted.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection open for use. Some restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the follwing eight series with some sub-series: Series I: Administrative Records, 1920-2016
Subseries A: Arboretum Advisory Committee, 1930-1991 Subseries B: Correspondence, 1920-1997 Subseries C: Fencing, 1937-1988 Subseries D: General, 1931-2016 Series II: Land Records, 1911-2003 Subseries A: Land Tracts 1911-1988 Subseries B: Maps and plans, 1931-1995 Subseries C: Gardens and plant lists, 1928-2003 Subseries D: General, 1944-1972 Series III: Programs and Events, 1937-2016 Series IV: Arboretum Publications, 1934-2017 Subseries A: Bulletins, 1934-2016 Subseries B: Guides and brochures, 1937-2017 Subseries C: Newsletters and books, 1961-2000 Series V: Press and Publicity, 1939-2002 Series VI: Undergraduate Natural Science Studies, 1954-1996 Series VII: Audio and visual material, ca. 1920-2009 Series VIII: Richard Goodwin's historical research of the Arboretum, 1890-1999
Arboretums; Botanical gardens; Gardens -- Connecticut -- New London; Caroline Black Garden -- (New London, Connecticut)
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1920-2016
  Scope and Contents
  Administrative records of the Arboretum at Connecticut College, including meeting minutes, notes, and reports of the Arboretum Advisory Committee and Board of Trustees; correspondence with donors; interviews and speeches; membership lists; notes on the ornamental fencing and entrance of the Arboretum; and records from dedications and anniversaries. This series has been divided into four subseries: administrative records, correspondence, fencing, and general. Campus Safety Reports (Box 18, folder 15) is open with some restrictions. Please consult archivist for access.
  - Subseries A: Arboretum Advisory Committee, 1930-1991
    - Anniversaries, 1956-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annual meeting, 1935-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Annual meeting, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Annual meeting, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Annual meeting (1 of 2), 1964-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Annual meeting (2 of 2), 1964-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual meeting, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual meeting, 1971-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual reports, 1936-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual reports, 1947-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual reports, 1957-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Finances, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Financial statements, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Minutes; includes annual meeting and advisory committee, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Minutes book, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Reports and meeting minutes, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 25th Anniversary Celebration, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 25th Anniversary tape; includes annotated transcript and slide list. See Series VII for audio reel., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence, 1920-1997
    - George Avery and Katharine Matthies, 1933-1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Anna Hempstead Branch and President's Office George Avery and Katharine Matthies, 1920-1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - General, 1931-1944 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - General, 1944-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Goodwind, Richard, 1974-1999 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Goodwin, Richard re: Arboretum vegetation survey, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Goodwin, Richard re: Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - President Marshall re: Bolleswood, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - William Nieiring, 1981-1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - William Nieiring re: Vermont Central Railroad encroachment, 1957-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Subseries C: Fencing, 1937-1988
    - Fencing the Arboretum, 1937-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ornamental fence, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Wetlands permit, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Subseries D: General, 1931-2016
    - Annual Reports, 1959-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1965-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports, 1996-2000 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports, 2001-2004 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Annual Reports, 2005-2008 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports, 2009-2013 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports, 2014-2016 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Assessment of the Connecticut College Arboretum by the American Association of Museums, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Biographical information: George Avery, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Board of Trustees actions and minutes, 1931-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Buck Lodge rules, circa 1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Bylaws and objectives, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Dedications, 1932, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Dedication: F.W. Olin Science Center, April 9-10, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Endowment funds, 1972-1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Interviews and speeches, circa 1940-1955 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes: George Avery, Captain Malloy, and Benham, 1967-1971 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Membership, 1932-1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Membership and financial statements, 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Memories of the Arboretum: Nellie Beetham Stark '56, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Minutes and reports, 1980-1987 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Natural areas program and arboretum research, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Project: Herbarium Curator's Toolkit 1.0, Carl Lewis; includes 3.5 floppy. See archivist for access., 1992 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Reports: annual and directors, 1962-1984 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Reports: directors, 25 and 35 years reports, 1956-1980 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Reports: priorities and projects, 1987-1992 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Safety incident reports. Some restrictions on this file; see archivist for access, 1988-1991 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Signage, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Speeches: 50th anniversary, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Stationary/ letterhead design, 1935-1941 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Visitors book and statistics, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Series II: Land Records, 1911-2003
  This series contains the records of Arboretum land acquisition and use. This includes correspondence, deeds, and maps, lists of flora and fauna, and financial records. Of particular interest are the original landscape plan and map developed by A.F. Brinckerhoff between 1931 and 1936. This series is divided into four subseries: Land tract records, Maps and plans, Gardens and plant lists, and General. Subseries A is organized by tract number then by date.
  - Subseries A: Land Tracts, 1911-1988
    - Tract 1: Branch Tract, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Tract 2: Bolleswood, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Tracts 3a and 3b: Comstock Tracts, 1926, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Tract 4: Ravine, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Tract 4: Ravine, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tract 5: Benham Avenue Extension, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Tract 5: Benham Avenue Extension, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tract 6: George S. Avery Tract, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Tracts 7 and 22: Matthies and Benham Tracts, 1946, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tract 8: Gallows Lane Extension, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Tract 8: College Court, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Tract 8: Thames Science Center (see also Tract 23), 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Tract 9: Williams Tract, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tract 10: Monroe Tract, 1950, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Tract 10: Monroe Tract, 1950, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Tract 11: Ribaudo Tract, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Tract 12: Hempstead Tract, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: archaeological survey proposal, Harold Juli, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: drudging damage, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: fundraising (1of 2), 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: fundraising (2 of 2), 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: fundraising and quit -claim deed, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island:Merrit-Chapman and Scot Corporation, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: publicity, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: railroad spraying damage, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Tract 13: Mamacoke Island: tidal marsh mapping, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Tract 14: Richard Hale Goodwin Tract, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tract 15: Kip house, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Tract 16: Brailsford Tract, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Tract 17: Burdick Tract, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Tract 18: Hirschfeld Tract, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Tract 19: Coffey Farm, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Tract 20: Hirschfeld Farm, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Tract 20: New London Water Tank, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Tract 21: Espinosa property, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Gallows Lane/Dandona properties, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Tract 23: Thames Science Center (1 of 2; see also Tract 8), 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Tract 23: Thames Science Center (2 of 2; see also Tract 8), 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Tract 24: Goodwin Tract, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Tract 25: Lodus Realty, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Tract 26: Sally L. Taylor Tract, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Tract 27: Worcester Lot, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Tract 28: Anderson Tract, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Tract 29: Niering Tract (1 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Tract 29: Niering Tract (2 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Tract 30: Applewood Tract, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Tract A: State Wildlife Sanctuary (1 of 2), 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Tract A: State Wildlife Sanctuary (2 of 2), 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Tract B: West Farms Land Trust Easement, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Maps and plans, 1931-1995
    - A.F. Brinckerhoff Plan, April 20, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Brinckerhoff Landscape Plans; Washington Entrance (DAR), 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Land tract maps, 1944, 1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Maps, 1931-1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Maps of Arboretum natural areas, 1953, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Map of tracts from anniversary bulletin, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Oversize maps, circa 1935-1951 (Box 0S2, Folder 1)
  - Subseries C: Gardens and plant lists, 1928-2003
    - Caroline Black Garden (1 of 2), 1928-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Caroline Black Garden (2 of 2), 1928-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Caroline Black Garden/ Garden for Peace, 1997-2001 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - History of the Caroline Black Botanic Garden, Linda Legassie, March, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Memorial gardens and collections, 1950-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 9-11 Garden, Bill Hall, 2002-2003 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Plant list of Connecticut College, 1937-1947 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Plant list of north dorm complex, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Shain Library plantings, 1976-1990 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Tree and plant lists, 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Subseries D: General, 1944-1972
    - Reports on the College Estate, 1944-1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Blank indenture form, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
- Series III: Programs and Events, 1937-2016
  Public and educational programs developed and hosted by the Arboretum, including the popular Nature Screen Tours, a series of public screenings of nature-based films, and various symposia, programs, and workshops.
  - Conferences, seminars, and symposia; includes Glenn Dreyer's opening remarks to a 1996 symposium, 1980-2013 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Nature Screen Tours, 1954-1960 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Programs and Symposia: posters, 1982-1983, 2016 (Box 0S2, Folder 1)
  - Programs and Symposia: posters, 1982-1983, 20161982-1983, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Short Courses and Workshops, 1956- 2013 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Summer Fellowships, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Summer Programs (1 of 2), 1937-1954 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Summer Programs (2 of 2), 1937-1954 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Arboretum Publications, 1934-2017
  This series contains the Connecticut College Arboretum publications. This includes seventy years of the Bulletin, the Connecticut Notable Trees project, guides to notable flora and fauna, and program brochures from 1990 to 2005. This series is divided into three subseries: Bulletins, Guides and brochures and newsletter and books. Subseries A is organized chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Bulletins, 1934-2016
    - Bulletin No. 1 – The Connecticut Arboretum at Connecticut College, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin No. 2 – The Connecticut Arboretum at Connecticut College, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Bulletin No. 3 – A Plant Handbook: Lists of Plants for Specific Landscape Uses, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Bulletin No. 4 – The Connecticut Arboretum: Its Tenth Anniversary, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Bulletin No. 5 – The Connecticut Arboretum: Recent Land Acquisitions, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Bulletin No. 6 – Check List of Woody Plants Growing in the Connecticut Arboretum and Guide to the Arboretum, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin No. 7 – The Connecticut Arboretum: Its History and the Establishment of the Natural Area, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Bulletin No. 8 – The Mamacoke Acquisition and Our Research Program, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Bulletin No. 9 – Six Points of Especial Botanical Interest in Connecticut, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Bulletin No. 10 – The Connecticut Arboretum: Birds of the Connecticut Arboretum and the Connecticut College Campus, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Bulletin No. 11 – A Roadside Crisis: The Use and Abuse of Herbicides, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Bulletin No. 12 – Connecticut's Coastal Marshes: A Vanishing Resource, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Bulletin No. 13 – What's Happening Along Our Roadsides?, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Bulletin No. 14 – Creating New Landscapes with Herbicides: A Homeowner's Guide, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Bulletin No. 15 – The Flora of the Connecticut Arboretum, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Bulletin No. 16 – A Guided Tour of the Connecticut Arboretum, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Bulletin No. 17 – Preserving Our Freshwater Wetlands, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin No. 18 – Seaweeds of the Connecticut Shore: A Wader's Guide, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bulletin No. 19 – Inland Wetland Plants of Connecticut, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bulletin No. 20 – Tidal Marsh Invertebrates of Connecticut, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bulletin No. 21 – Energy Conservation on the Home Grounds: The Role of Naturalistic Landscaping, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Bulletin No. 22 – Our Dynamic Tidal Marshes: Vegetation Changes as Revealed by Plant Analysis, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin No. 23 – Plants and Animals of the Estuary, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Bulletin No. 24 – Garden Guide to Woody Plants: A Plant Handbook –Selection and Care of Woody Plants, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Bulletin No. 25 – Salt Marsh Plants of Connecticut, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Bulletin No. 26 – Recycling Mycelium: A Fermentation Byproduct becomes an Organic Resource, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Bulletin No. 27 – Birds of Connecticut Salt Marshes, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Bulletin No. 28 – The Connecticut Arboretum: Its First Fifty Years, 1931-1981, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin No. 29 – Common Mushrooms of New England, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Bulletin No. 30 – Native Shrubs for Landscaping, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Bulletin No. 31 – Birds of the Connecticut College Arboretum, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bulletin No. 32 – The Connecticut College Arboretum: Its Sixth Decade and a Detailed History of the Land, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Bulletin No. 33 – Archaeology in the Connecticut College Arboretum, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin No. 34 – Tidal Marshes of Long Island Sound: Ecology, History, and Restoration, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Bulletin No. 35 – Native Woody Plant Collection Checklist, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin No. 36 – Amphibians and Reptiles of the Connecticut College Arboretum, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Bulletin No. 37 – Living Resources and Habitats of the Lower Connecticut River, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Bulletin No. 38 – The Hidden World of Plants: A Scanning Electron Microscope Survey of the Native Plant Collection, Connecticut College Arboretum, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Bulletin No. 39 – Seaweeds of Long Island Sound, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Bulletin No. 40 – Salt Marsh Plants of Long Island Sound, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin No. 40 – Salt Marsh Plants of Long Island Sound, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bulletin No. 40 – Salt Marsh Plants of Long Island Sound, 2016 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Subseries B: Guides and brochures, 1937-2017
    - Guides, 1961-2016 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Guides, 1961-2016 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Program brochures, 1990-1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Program brochures, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Program brochures, 2000-2005 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Program brochures, 2006-2017 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Publications; includes woody plant list guide, announcements, and brochures, 1937-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Newsletters and books, 1961-2000
    - Arboretum Contact Newsletter, Vol. 3 Issues 1 and 2, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Connecticut's Notable Trees: Memoirs of the Connecticut Botanical Society No. 2, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - William Niering reprints; includes Pollen Diagram from Southeast Connecticut and Ecological Studies in the Connecticut Arboretum Natural Area, 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Reprint – Tidal Marshes of Connecticut: A Primer about the Plants that Grow in Our Wetlands, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series V: Press and Publicity, 1939-2002
  Press coverage of Arboretum programs, publications, and land acquisition efforts, as well as Arboretum and Connecticut College-issued press releases.
  - Arboretum calendar, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - News clippings, 1967-1993 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - News clippings and programs, 1939-1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - News releases and articles on staff, 1950-1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Undergraduate Natural Science Studies, 1954-1996
  Organized alphabetically by author.
  - Althausen, Anne M. – "Territorial and Foraging Behavior Exhibited by a Polydomous Species of Myrmica in the Connecticut Arboretum", 1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Altvater, Laura D. – "Naturalistic Landscaping and the Renovation of the Edgerton and Stengel Woodland Wildflower Garden of the Connecticut College Arboretum", 1996 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Attai, Linnette J. and Wenley Ferguson – "Relationship Between Small Mammal Populations and the Size of Isolated Forest Tracts", 1987 (Box 12, Folder 3)